The best plans of 2025 Five such health
insurances which are above the super in the market
This video is going to be very important for you
You are tired of searching for health insurance plans and
you are unable to take a decision The
best plans of 2025
Friends, today in this explosive video
I am going to compare five such health insurances which are
above the super in the market
What are the features in those plans, what are the benefits
and what unique features are available
So all the points are going to be
analyzed one by one A discussion is going to happen
so that
if you want to purchase a health insurance at least then this
video is going to be very important for you
So friends this explosive video
requires only 5 minutes of yours I am not
saying that you should subscribe to my channel
If you are tired of searching for a health insurance plan and
you are unable to take a decision
Or your benefits are not available in the health
insurance company policy which you are already running
And  If you are
not able to get your disturbed claim, then this video is going to be very important for you.
Watch the video till the end so that
you can take the best decision regarding health insurance.
Friends, I, Govinda Roy Health
Insurance, have been working in the life insurance industry for more than
15 years and till date,
we have got claims settled for many people
and
we are still serving people. If
you are searching for the best health insurance plan and are
unable to take a decision, then you
can contact our team. Our team will
help you in purchasing the best health insurance.
Plus, if you are a life
insurance agent, you are a mutual fund
distributor but are
not doing health insurance work today,
or you are already working but you are
not successful, then you should contact us.
Our team will help you. You
can work with us as an associate.
We recruit agents on an all India level basis and by
training and motivating the agents, we provide the
best health
insurance.  Makes you successful in your career
I am an MDRT HFR advisor
so I will give you practical knowledge of how you can be
successful in the market so
friends without taking much time let's
start the video so friends if we talk about the
five plans which we are going to compare the
first plan out of the five plans the name of the plan is Nibha Bappa
Aspire plan second one is HDFC Air Go
company's Optima Secure and third one is
ICICI Lord's Iled plan fourth one is
Aditya Bilal Capital's Active One plan
and fifth one is Care Health's Care
Supreme plan so there is going to be a comparison of five plans
you should watch the video till the end
so that you can take the best one i.e. if you want to take a decision then
this video is going to be very explosive for you so
friends if we talk about
unique features then talk about unique features
what unique features are available in the Air plan right
so friends
if we talk about the unique feature of Air plan the unique feature
is Lock the Clock i.e. at which age
you take the premium i.e. policy you will pay the
premium at the same age  The
premium will be frozen and
until you claim the premium, the
premium will remain the same. This is a very
unique feature. If we
talk about the next unique feature in the Aspire plan,
friends, it is Borderless, that is, there is a rider
Borderless. If you opt for the rider
in Niva, then
you can get treatment abroad as well. Another benefit
in the Aspire plan is Miracle
Benefit, that is,
basically the company covers maternity under Miracle Benefit, which
covers your maternity after nine months.
Along with maternity, in this Miracle
Benefit, the company also covers all the benefits from adoption to
right adoption cut.
Another benefit
in the Air plan is Booster Plus, that is,
in Booster Plus, your sum assured gets carried
forward every year, that is, your sum assured will keep
increasing 10 times, that is,
if you have a policy of Rs 10 lakh, then Rs 10 lakh will become Rs
20 lakh and Rs 30 lakh.  It will become 40, it will become
50, by doing this your
policy of 10 lakh will become one crore plus
basic sum of 10 lakh in 10 years, that is, your policy will become 1 crore 10
lakh after 10 years.
Another optional rider, if you choose
in NIPA policy, is DM rider. If
you take disease management rider, then
suppose you have BP and
sugar etc., then you can cover it from day one.
If you take DM rider, then there is a
benefit in Aspire plan, that is
Safe Guard and Safe Guard Plus benefit.
Basically, it will be like non-payable
items like consumables etc., then
you can cover that too in NB plan.
Right, so this is basically the unique
features of NB in ​​Aspire plan,
friends, we go to the next plan, which is
Optimal Secure.
What unique features are available
in Optimal Secure? If we talk about the unique features in Optimal Secure,
2x coverage means
suppose you have taken coverage of 10 lakhs, then
from day one the company provides you coverage of 20 lakhs.
Your coverage from day one will be
2x coverage. Right,
suppose you have taken Super Secure, then if you
take the Super Secure option, then
you get 3x coverage from day one, that is, if you have
taken a policy of 10 lakhs, then you get coverage of 30 lakhs
from day one.
Plus, if we talk about loyalty addition in this,
it will be done at 50% and the
maximum that will reach you reaches 100%.
Loyalty addition means whether you
take a claim or not, the
company will increase your sum by 50% every year. Coming to the next plan,
friends, the next plan is
iLabad's Event Plan. Let
us see what unique features are there in it. The
unique feature in it is basically Power Booster, that is,
if you have taken Power Booster, then your sum
sum which will keep increasing your sum sum every year, it will keep increasing
your sum sum till infinite times.  That
is, if you have
taken Power Booster Rider, then there is another
benefit in ICICI Lord plan, that is
civil discount. If your civil is
good, then the company provides you additional discount
in your policy. Right, the
next benefit in ICICI Lord
is Infinite Care. Right, if
you have taken Infinite Care optional rider, then once in a
lifetime, if you have any one claim in your policy, then in this, the
company provides you claim for infinite time in
one claim. Plus, friends, if we talk about
unlimited sum assured, your unlimited sum assured is available in ICICI Lord, that is,
you can opt for sum assured for unlimited time.
Next, friends, let us talk about what unique features are available in AB
Capital i.e. Aditya Bala Capital's Active
Bhan plan.
First, if we talk about it, it is
Chronic Care Rider. If you have taken Chronic Care
Rider, then you can remove
your policy in Chronic Care Rider.
Suppose that you remove that, and if
you take Chronic Care Rider again, then you can do it as soon as possible.  You
can cover the disease. The
next benefit is Super
Credit, that is, the maximum of your policy becomes
five times yours. The sum will be
yours if you have taken the Super Credit
option, if you have taken a rider, then friends, the
next plan is Care Supreme.
If we talk about the
features available in Care Supreme, it is Super NCP, that is,
your policy is
seven times. If you have also taken Super NC, then
your policy is seven times, that is, if you have a
policy of Rs. 10 lakh, then you will have a policy of Rs. 70 lakh.
Right, if you have also taken Super NC, then there is
another benefit in it, that is, instant
cover, that is, you can reduce the pre-assisting conditions. You can get
instant cover for this.
Friends, if
we talk about day care in all the plans, day
care means 24 hours below if there is
hospitalization, basically it is
called day care. So,
day care is covered in all the plans. Now, the next thing that comes is
AYUSH treatment. AYUSH means
Ayurvedic, Unani, Homeopathy and Siddha
treatment, that is also covered in all the plans.  The
next benefit you get to the same show
is domiciliary hospitalization, which means any treatment is done while staying at home.
Basically, that treatment is
called domiciliary hospitalization. Domiciliary hospitalization is covered
up to the same shot in all the plans. The
next
benefit, friends, is organ donor, which means
if someone wants to get an organ or is
donating an organ, then the
company covers both the things up to the same shot.
This thing is available in all the plans. The next
benefit is refill benefit, which is called
restore, some call it reinstate. So,
this refill benefit, if we talk about, is covered
in all the plans for the same person, same illness.
If we talk about pre and post hospitalization,
friends, that is pre and post
hospitalization. Pre
and post hospitalization is available in all the plans.
If we talk about modern treatment, that is
up to the same shot, which means if someone has a robotic
surgery or modern treatment, then
all these things are
not covered in many policies today.
But in all these policies, there is
Modern Treatment After The Sash cover.
Friends, if we purchase any policy, then first of all
we look at the claim settlement
ratio. If we talk about claim ratio,
claim settlement ratio is a different thing. So,
if we talk about the
latest published data of ID, then
in Aspire plan, the
end claim ratio in NIPA is
5902.
According to the latest published data of ID, it is
8.98 in ADFC Ergo. If we talk about ICICI Lord, it is
78.8. If we talk about Adit Birla Capital,
it is 68.3 and Care Health
Insurance is
57.6. So here, if we
talk about ICICI sorry HDFC Ergo,
it has 8.98 end claim ratio, that is,
how much premium they raised from the market
and how much claim they paid. If
we see here, the highest  It is
of ADFC Ergo, right after that the next
number that comes is of ICICI Lombard, that is, whatever
premium they
raised from the market, how much claim they gave,
but this is basically the inc claim ratio,
if we talk about 60, that is, if it
goes above 60, if it is between 60 to 80, then
basically it is considered healthy, if it
exceeds that then the
chances of the company incurring loss are high, so
what will happen after that is that the burden of premium
may increase on you, the company
can increase your premium because
from where will the company provide the claim on its own,
right, if the inc claim ratio is
high then there is loss, if it is too
low then also there is loss, that is, the
company did not pass much claim, if it is too low,
if it is below 50 then it is very worst,
right, so it is also
important to see that friends, if we talk about all the
plans, if we talk about room rate, the
next point that comes is
room rent, right, let's talk about room rent
in Aspire plan, if we talk about room  There is
no room rate capping on rent. There is no
room rate capping in this plan. Next, if we
talk about ADAC's Optimum Soccer, there is no
room rate capping in it too.
You can take any room. In
the room rent in ACC Lord's Event plan,
you will get single AC private rooms.
You are going to get single AC private rooms.
Next, if we talk about Aditya Billa Capital, there is
no room rate capping in it. There is no room rate capping in it.
Talking about Care Health Insurance's Supreme plan, there is no room
rate capping in it. Only one plan has a
single private AC room, that is ICC
Labad's Livet plan. Right, friends, now let us
look at the eligibility criteria. Who
can purchase this plan?
Which age group's Nipa Aer plan has entry
age from 18 to 65 years. Entry age
after that, entry is not possible.
Entry age of child is from 9
to 30 years. Even after that, if you wish, the
child can stay. If there is a
dependent child, then he can stay. Right,
Next  If we talk about HDFC Optiemus
Secure, there is no limit of 18 years and above,
any person of any age group can
enter, if we talk about the age of the child, he can
enter from 91 to 25 years, the maximum age can be
years and above, if we talk about ASI Lord, the age
of the child is from 91 days to 30 years, if there is any person who can stay, the
child can enter in this plan,
Aditya Bila Capital has 18 years
and above, if we talk about Care Health
Insurance, there is no
limit of 18 years and above, if we talk about the
right child, if we talk about the right child, from 91 days to
24 years, the child can
stay as a dependent child, right friends,
if we talk about same soda, you can
take same soda from 3 lakh to 1 crore in Aspire plan, from
5 lakh to 2 crore in Optiemus Secure, from 5 lakh to 5 crore
in ICICI Lombard
Unlimited sum assured is available in Aditya Bala
Capital. The maximum sum assured is from Rs 7 lakh to Rs 6 crore
which can be taken in Aditya Capital Active
One and if we
talk about the Supreme plan in which the
sum assured is from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 1 crore,
friends, if you talk about
bonus, that is, any community bonus, or no
bonus which we call it, then if we talk about Aspire plan in
which there are four variants,
in Aspire plan if we talk about four
variants in which there is Gold Plus, Diamond
Plus, like right, Platinum Plus,
Titanium Plus, right, if we
talk about Gold Plus, if there is a person between 18 to 35 years of age, then
five times sum assured will be an add-on in it, if there is
36 to 45 then it will be up to 3x and if there is 46
Plus then it will be up to 2x which will be in Gold Plus
plan,
if we talk about Platinum and Titanium Plus in which there is 18 to 35 then it will be
up to 10x and 36 to 45 will be up
to 5x and  46 plus will be up to 3x the sum assured
which will increase i.e.
suppose if a person below 35 years of age takes Titanium or
Platinum Plus then its
sum assured increases 10 times and the basic sum assured is 10
lakhs i.e. after 10 years the sum assured becomes 1 crore 10 lakhs.
Oh sorry expiry plan
if you take Nibha Upa which is Platinum
or Diamond Plus if you opt for it then let
us talk about HDFC and Optiemus Secure
's edition of 50% on second year and third year
renewal right in this 50% will increase twice,
we have already discussed it, let us
talk about ICICI Loard, in this the maximum will be
100% on 20%, it will increase every year on 20%, if we
talk about inbuilt coverage right
if we take optional rider then it is a different matter if
we talk about Bala Capital Active Max then
100% off sum assured will be given in it, maximum
up to 500 off sum assured will be given in it  Not reduced
in case of any claim, that is,
if we talk about Aditya Billa Capital's Active Max, in
which five times the sum will be reduced and
it will not be reduced on taking the claim,
if we talk about Care Supreme plan, the
maximum will be 100% on 50, in which your inbuilt
50% will increase twice and the
maximum will be 100%, if you take a rider, then
your sum will be reduced,
right, the refill benefit which is restored,
we have already discussed, in Nipa Air
plan, your unlimited number of times will be
restored, like unlimited times will be
restored and Optimus Secure, sorry
Optimus Secure of ADFC EGO,
if we talk about Optimus Secure, in that, once in a year, it will be
equal to the sum, any illness, any illness, it will be
once in a year, if we
talk about ICICI Loard, in which there is unlimited number
of times, in ICICI Loard,
unlimited times sum will be
restored in it, plus any illness, right
any illness will be in it, Aditya  In Bala Capital, there are
unlimited number of times in a year
for any illness, in that too from unlimited times
and any illness and if we
talk about Care Supreme, it will be covered unlimited times,
only here if we talk about
HDFC Optiemus Secure, there will be once in a year sum assured
and it will be covered in all, right
friends, now let's talk about emergency road ambulance,
right, all the companies are covering emergency road ambulance,
in this, which
companies are covering whom, let's just talk about that,
in the app, the same amount will be covered, you will
actually get it, in HDFC Bank,
the same amount will be covered, in ICICI Lombard,
your same amount will be covered,
if we talk about Bala Capital, in that, you will be covered,
the actual amount is covered, in all of them, there is actual same amount,
but in Care Supreme,
basically the sum assured will be below 15 lakhs up to 10000
and 50 lakhs and now the sum assured will be up to
only one plan in this.  There is capping in
which if the sum assured in Care Supreme is below 15 lakhs
then you will get Rs. 0 ...  It
is charging 15000 in ADAC AGO
and if we talk about ICICI Lord on
the listed cashless basis, they will do your
test, if we talk about Aditya Bilal
Capital Active Max in which the available
VAS will be covered once a year by the company
and here if we talk about Care Supreme,
there also the company provides you wellness test,
now friends, that is
pre and post hospitalization, if we talk about pre and post
hospitalization, then in NIBA Bupa it is
60 and 180 days,
whatever you spend before going from hospital to hospital goes into
your
resop, after discharge the
medicines that the doctor takes, whatever that
treatment is, suppose you have
physiotherapy and if there is any over
treatment then it is
called post hospitalization, so post
hospitalization also and pre
hospitalization is covered by the company,
in NIBA it is 6180 days, in HDFC Bank it is 60 and 1880 days
and in ICICI Lombard it is 90 and 180 days
in Aditya Bilal Capital  9180 days and
Care Supreme have cover for 60 and 180 days
e-consultation, so basically in all the plans
e-consolidation is mostly not available in it, if
we see in one plan in which
e-consolidation is not available in Aditya Bal Capital
and
in all the other plans e-consultation unlimited e-
consultation is mostly available, right wellness
benefit, if you talk about wellness
benefit in this take healthy live healthy benefits,
if you remain healthy then the company provides you discount in the next plan in
which you have to count steps,
if you count steps and
remain healthy then the company provides you discount,
you can get discount up to 30 in it,
it is not available in only one plan, that is ADFC
Optimum Secure, this wellness
benefit is not available in it, right in most of the other
plans wellness benefit
is covered in it, if you download the company's website then
you have to count steps  If you have a problem and want to
stay healthy then you get this reward i.e. you
get a discount in your premium i.e. stay healthy and keep getting
discount in premium as well. Friends, there is
another option that is OPD cover. Most of the times
our clients ask, Bhaiya Sir, is there
OPD cover in the plans? OPD is a
very big part. If you
want, you can
add age rider in Aspire plan. If you want, you
can cover up OPD by taking a rider. Next, if we
talk about HDFC Optima Secure
Right, in that too Optima Edge and
Optima Well Being Rider are available.
You can take it with a rider in this also. Mostly,
you can take OPD right with a rider
in all the plans, only yours is
not available in Aditya Bala Capital, hence
you cannot take a rider. Now comes the right of OPD,
which is non-payable items, which is called
non-medical expenses right. So,
if we look at the Aspire plan,
you can cover non-payable items by taking a rider in Safeguard Plus.
In HDFC Argo, your protect benefit is
inbuilt and covered as per error B, that is,
your AAC ER has inbuilt coverage
which is your rider for non-payable items. You do
not need to take an additional rider in which
inbuilt cover is available. Non-payable items will
also be covered in ICICI Lord.
You will have to take a rider in that.
If we talk about Aditya Billa Capital,
covered in build is inbuilt cover in it too,
which is available in Max plan of Aditya Billa
Capital, Active and Max in which
covered is inbuilt.  In Care Supreme,
if you take the claim shield rider, then
you will get a credit in that too, right, so friends, the
next very important
point is copayment, right, if you
talk about Niba Uba, there is no copayment in it, there is no
copayment in mostly all,
only if we talk about ICICI Loard,
in this you can get a copayment through rider, by
taking any rider you
can take it, there is no copayment for anything else,
right, there is another option, that is deductible, right,
if you choose deductible, then
your premium becomes cheaper, but it is
not right for you to do so, right, if you
look at the deductible option, it is available in this plan, it is
deductible in AC Ego also,
and if we talk about it, it is not available in ICICI Loard, it
is not available in Aditya Bala Capital, and if we talk about the
plan available in Care Supreme, the deductible option is available only in two plans, in
which Aspire and
HFC Airg's Optimum S, it is deductible in both.  The
option of specific illness is available,
right, if you have any planned
surgery etc., then after how many years is it
covered, what is the waiting period, it
is available in all, if we talk like NIBA UPA has
24 months, ADAC has 24 months,
in all the plans there is a 24 months pre-exist i.e.
specific illness waiting period
available, in all there is a 24
months waiting period for specific illness, right, PD
waiting period, if there is any pre-existing disease, then
what is the waiting period, it is
four years in Gold Plus and after that if
we talk about Diamond Platinum and
Titanium, in this there is a waiting
period of 9 years for pre-existing in 9 plans
and in all the other plans, 3 years
pre-existing waiting period is available,
right, so let's talk about maternity coverage,
friends, next let's
talk about maternity coverage, in this it
is available in your Acer plan, it is not available in all the other plans
and if we talk about ICICI
Lord  You can add a rider along with the
maternity plan. You can add a
maternity cover after nine months in Niba Upa. So, the biggest plus point
in Nip is that if you are thinking about maternity, then you
can cover maternity after nine months. Right, there
is an option in it which is Miracle Benefit. You will have to
take the rider. Talking about global coverage, it
is available in Aspire plan and
in this you will have to take the rider.
Available in ADFC Ego. Now ADFC Secure Global
and Global Plus are also available in AFC Ego. If you
want, you can add on the rider.
Global coverage is not there in all the other plans. Right,
friends, if we talk about discount, then
basically you can see the discount in all the plans. If you take a plan of
one year to two years or three years, right,
if you take a plan of two years or three years, discount is available to you
in all the plans.
You can get long term discount, so if
you take a plan
for a longer period of time.  If you take this plan,
you will get a discount. Now friends, the next
biggest part of ours is the
premium. Now let's see how much premium can be charged for which age group. So,
I have selected one age group. If we
see, then in comparison, if we see the premium of Zone One, then
we have applied Safeguard Plus in it. In Ni Aspire plan,
if HDFC's Optimum Secured
Claim has been done, it has an inbuilt Claim Protector.
We have added IC Lard in it. If we talk about
Adi Capital, it has an inbuilt coverage,
which is Safeguard, which is a non-viable blanket cover.
We have
added non-payable items along with them. In the sum, we have added Claim Shield.
We have also added all the non-payable items. So, if we
talk about the premium of Zone One, then
in Ni Aspire plan it is coming to Rs. 27710.
If we talk about age, the
sum assured is Rs. 10 lakh. And
if we talk about family size, it is
31, which is an adult. Basically, if we talk about
husband.  The age of the husband is 31, the age of the wife is 28 and the
age of the child is 3 years, we have
taken the 2nd plan, suppose we have
calculated the premium according to the cover, then it is
coming to 27710, in NI plan it is
coming to
390 i.e. the premium is 90, in ADAC AGO it is
coming to 7686, in IIC Lord's Event plan it is
coming to 1952, in Aditya Pila Capital it is
coming to 1952, if we
talk about Cash Supreme, the
premium is coming to 6998, right, this is the premium of Zone One, so
you
can also compare the premium according to you, right,
friends, this comparison has become a very
long video, but I hope
I could clear your doubts about
what are the benefits in health insurance and
what is not covered, I have already
discussed a lot of points, if I have missed any point, then
definitely you can contact me
with someone in case of a medical emergency  If this happens,
what will he do? He will not look at his accumulated capital,
his accumulated money, mutual funds, LIC,
etc. He will not look at all the land, if he has a lot,
he can sell it, he can even mortgage it, he
can sell it. So, to
protect your clients, to protect their money, at least you should
provide health insurance, right, today itself.
Get a health insurance agency.
If you haven't taken a health insurance policy
yet, you should search. You are procrastinating, get it
today. Brother, come and
say, I will
come for you the day after tomorrow, brother. After that, I will
come on the 7th, I will come next month, I will come next year, I can come
anytime. So, you should take a decision today itself.
I have compared five plans. If you have
any doubts in this, then you can contact us. We have a
complete team with 15 years of experience in the market,
so
we will provide you excellent guidance and
make you successful in your health insurance career. I am an MDRT HB
advisor, so I will give you practical knowledge on
how you can be successful in the market.
So friends.  Or if you want to
take an agency or a policy, you can
make us a topic, please comment so that
I can prepare the next video accordingly
and see you
in the next video. Till then take care of yourself.
See you in the next video and
with a new topic. Till then bye bye
Jai Hind Vande Mataram
[Music]